Finding Aid for Church Women United In Ann Arbor Records, 1941-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Church Women United In Ann Arbor records 1941-2004
Church Women United In Ann Arbor.
4.5 linear ft.
88166 Bk 2
Interdenominational church women's organization, formerly known as United Church Women of Ann Arbor. Minutes, reports, yearbooks, scrapbooks, photographs, sound recordings, and other files relating to activities and interests.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group (donor no. 3864 ) was first deposited with the library in 1961. Periodic additions have been received.
The record group is open to research.
Church Women United in Ann Arbor was begun in 1942 by several Protestant churches who had co-sponsored a World Day of Prayer since 1919. In addition to this ecumenical event, celebrations of world community and fellowship as well as support for world-wide missions were early projects. Local efforts included support for migrant workers, juvenile delinquents, and international students.
The record group begins with a file relating to the organization's history and administrative structure. This is followed by a bound volume containing minutes for the years of 1941 to 1950. The record group is then arranged into yearly files dating from 1950 to 2004. These files include such materials as mimeographed board of directors reports as well as a variety of newsletters, bulletins, and financial reports. An important source of information about the organization is a series of scrapbooks with clippings and some photographs detailing group activities in the period of 1960 to 2001.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); United Church Women of Ann Arbor.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; Church Women United in Ann Arbor.; Women--Religious life--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre
Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Background and organizational
  - Organization structure and history (Box 1)
  - Record book, 1941-1950 (Box 1)
  - Skits (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Yearly files
  - 1950-1972, 19 folders (Box 1)
  - 1973-1998, 34 folders (Box 2)
  - 1999-2004, 6 folders (Box 3)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1960-1972 (Box 4)
  - 1961 (Box 4)
  - 1961-1985 (scattered) (Box 4)
  - 1961-2001 (Box 4)
  - 1970-1972 (Box 4)
  - 1991-1993 (Box 4)
  - 1998-2003 (Doris Kennedy scrapbook) (Box 4)
- Photographs
  - Album of monthly meetings and other events (Box 4)
  - Album of photographs of various meetings and featuring table settings (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous photos of organization functions (Box 4)
  - Slides of presentation: "We Celebrate and Act Together" (Box 4)
- Activities Files
  - Ann Arbor-Washtenaw Council of Churches, 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - Ann Arbor-Washtenaw Council of Churches, 1966-1967 (Box 5)
  - Christian Social Relations, 1962-1965 (Box 5)
  - Christian World Missions (Box 5)
  - Church Women United in Michigan, 1961-1966 (Box 5)
  - Committee for Responsibility (Box 5)
  - Community Services, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 5)
  - Leadership Institute, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Mission Institute, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Mission Institute, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Mission Institute, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Obituaries and obsequies of members (Box 5)
  - Religion and Peace (Box 5)
  - United Nations Committee (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- Sound recordings, sound cassettes
  - 30th Anniversary luncheon program featuring Nan Sparrow talk "Next 30 Years" April 12, 1972 (Box 5)
  - 1984 Ecumenical Assembly, Sr. Marjorie Tuite (Box 5)
  - 1984 Ecumenical Assembly, Julia Esquivel (Box 5)
  - 1984 Ecumenical Assembly, Shirley Chisholm (Box 5)
  - WUOM broadcast, April 10, 1984 (Box 5)